Maikel Fernandez SYSTEM ENGINEER



Developer Analyst



About me

Have attitude, think, believe and achieve

Software developer experience in Java/J2EE software development and technologies such as spring boot, kafka messaging system, docker, CI/CD, mongoDB, AWS, redis cache, testing (mockito, mockserver), etc. I am a resultsoriented person, highly flexible and with analytical skills.

I have had the opportunity to belong to large and complex information systems with end-to-end implementation in the product life cycle for different sectors such as Insurance. Bankina and Textile lately, including Bank Sabadell insurance, Openbank, Bank Santander and Inditex (Zara, Bershka, Pull&bear and all associated chain stores)

Contact

maykelfdz@hotmail.com



+34 677 250 629



Alicante, Spain



Portfolio:

https://maykelfdz.github.io/portfolio/







EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

ATSistema - from april 2021 Spain - Remote

INDITEX. Development, analysis and implementation of a new architecture for order preparation, management and distribution systems (picking, packing and delivery) for all stores internationally and for all companies within the Inditex group.

- > Technologies: Java 11, Spring Boot, Kafka, IBM MQ, MongoDB, Docker, CI/CD (Github Actios, OpenShift, Maven), Grafana, Gaylog, Testing (Junit 5, Mockito, MockServer).
- > Analysis, design, development or maintenance of applications.
- > High performance development, focused on high data flow.
- > Full cycle of analysis, development, testing and production start-up.
- > Identification and implementation of innovation and improvements.
- > Taking functional requirements and technical analysis.
- > Clean Code (SOLID), Code Review.

Business & integration arch analyst

accenture

Accenture - June 2019 a april 2021 Spain - Remote

Grupo Santander, Openbank - Onboarding Multicountry Development, analysis and implementation of the Onboarding system (opening an account in a bank) primarily in Argentina and Spain.

- > Technologies: Java 8, Spring Boot, AWS infrastructure, DynamoDB, Docker, Open Feign, Testing (Junit, Mockito, WireMock), Redis
- > Activities include analysis, coding, integration and implementation, using methodologies and tools.
- > Development based on functional programming
- > Full cycle of analysis, development, testing and production start-up.
- > Taking functional requirements and technical analysis.

Java Analyst Developer

Everis NTT Data Company - August 2018 to June 2019

Banc Sabadell - Insurance - Home and auto Insurance multichannels in

- > Technologies: Java 6, Tibco infrastructure, Microservices SOA.
- > Takes requirements, models and is in charge of providing optimal technological solutions aligned with the business
- > Ensures the quality of the solution and perform their tasks with great
- > Development of functional changes and technical design.
- > Java team management.

Junior Java Developer

Campomar

Everis NTT Data Company - January 2018 to august 2018

Banc Sabadell - Insurance - Home and auto Insurance multichannels in Production.

- > Coding, integration and implementation.
- > Taking of functional and technical requirements.

Web App Developer Scholarship

Fundación Esplai - October 2017 to January 2018 Personal project of appointments or reservations

- > Design and development
- > Tools: MySql, Hibernate, Maven, GitLab, Java, Html, CSS, Javascript, Jquery, HQL, JSP

Web Developer

Workana - April 2017 to July 2017

Freelance

> Web development, logo design, banner flyer and others

Web Developer

AdwordSpain - January 2017 to April 2017 - Spain

Web Development, Flyer and Logo Design, Mobile Application (Wordpress, Photoshop)

Website Design and Development

Residences Ciubalgue - 2016

Frelance

> Blog design and development (Wordpress)

MySQL database administrator

Hotel Campomar - 2015

 $oldsymbol{>}$ Implementation of MySQL Database for Reservation and Lodging System

General Manager

Hotel Campomar 2008 to 2016 - Venezuela

Management and administration (Hotel, bar, restaurant, disco)

> I started as a Cashier, then Administrative Sub-Manager until I reached the last

SKILL **Develoment**

- Microservices
- . Api RestFull
- Java 11
- Spring boot
- . Testing (Mockito, Mockserver)
- . CI/CD (GitHub, Jenkins, Maven)
- Messaging System (Kafka, IBM MQ)
- Oracle
- . MongoDB
- . AWS DynamoDB
- Redis, Datagrid
- . Scrum
- . Git
- . SonarQube
- SOLID

Transversal

- Leadership
- Planification and organization
- . People Management
- Commitment
- . Teamwork
- . Initiative and proactivity.
- . Conflict resolution
- Communication
- Decision making

Language

- **Spanish Native**
- . English B1

Design

- . Photoshop
- . Illustrator
- . After effects

EDUCATION

Systems Engineer

University Santa Maria - 2011 to 2017 Caracas - Venezuela

IT management

Mongo DB

Udemy.com - from May 2022

ude.my/UC-e076d898-f880-4d48-8dda-66c1d52a08f9

Apache Kafka with java, Spring framework y AWS

Udemy.com - from May 2022

ude.my/UC-97e0dd81-2ab7-4d7b-ac02-872cf8e6a7c8

DevOps with Docker, Jenkins, Kubernetes, git, GitFlow CI/CD

Udemy.com - from May 2022

ude.my/UC-f584ead1-1d51-4be2-9c4d-56a1e4f50e39

Reactive Programming with Spring Boot 2 and Spring WebFlux

Udemy.com - from April 2021

ude.my/UC-e389fde7-f214-47ba-b20b-1ca89bbe196f

Docker Introduction

Udemy.com - from Jun 2019

ude.my/UC-57M9OTHI/

Technological Skills and Competencies in Java & SQL

Fundación Esplai - from Oct 2017

Web Development with MySql, Hibernate, Maven, GitLab, Java, Html, CSS, Javascript, Jquery, HQL, JSP

fundación**esplai**

UNIVERSIDAD SANTA MARÍA

ûdemy

Introduction to Web Development

Institute of International Economics of the University of Alicante - Oct 2016Web Development with HTML, CSS, Javascript